Gavin Stark

gavin@gstark.com 727-560-3116 Saint Petersburg, FL, 33703 https://www.linkedin.com/in/gastark https://github.com/gstark

Analytical and keen professional with broad experience in creating, maintaining, auditing, and improving systems to fulfil clients' requirements. Proficient in creating and deploying applications, coordinating developer teams, determining requirements, and interacting with implementation team to design sessions. Well versed in analyzing development issues, designing system specifications and standards, testing product prototypes, and writing code. Ability to implement agile methodologies to drive team efficiency while introducing improvements to optimize software and web applications. Effective communicator with strong critical problem-solving skills along with excellent commitment to team environment dynamics.

Technical Proficiencies

Mentorship. Management. Ruby. Ruby on Rails. Linux. C. C++. JavaScript. TypeScript. Java. C#. HTML. CSS. TDD. Docker. React. Heroku. Nginx. VMWare. MySQL. PostgreSQL. Windows.

Career Experience

Senior Instructor, Suncoast Developers Guild, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2018 - Present

Devise and implement interactive and engaging curriculum for multiple courses. Contributed to a 95% placement rate by identifying, recommending, and guiding students to secure positions as junior developers. Expanded market from full-time in-person classes into remote, part-time courses by developing an open-source curriculum for Ruby, C#, Entity Framework, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, Responsive Web, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Deployment, and Algorithmic Thinking. Reduced overhead by developing student management system to effectively handle multiple operations, including enrollment, homework assignment, grading, and student progress reports.

- Contributed to internal app generator: app-app. Based on react-scripts, builds student starter projects.
- Enabled part-time courses by producing over 400 hours of recorded lectures with detailed slides and corresponding reading and code samples.

Senior Developer, STRATACACHE, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2017 - Present

Enabled new markets by creating and maintaining a custom Ubuntu-based OS that supported 32-bit Intel, 64-bit Intel, and then ARM-64 based embedded systems. Achieved first-to-market amongst other divisions in a transition to the ARM platform by developing and implementing custom kernel patches for ARM-64 systems.

• Improved the marketability of the NEOCAST digital signage management system by reimplementing, as the primary developer, the software as a JSON-API back-end in Ruby on Rails and

- a front-end in over 30,000 lines of TypeScript and React using Bootstrap.
- Maintained software development costs by supporting a Ruby on Rails project for over 15 years. From Rails version 0.9 through Rails version 6.1
- Lowered hardware platform costs by maintaining a single application architecture for 32-bit Intel, 64-bit Intel, ARM-64, and Android devices.
- Reduced hosting budget by building automation software for deploying and scaling AWS resources to host a Docker-based application.

Instructor and Product Development, The Iron Yard, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2015 - 2017

Increased enrollment at one of the most profitable campuses at the largest in-person code school through developing and implementing a curriculum for Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, Algorithmic Thinking, and Deployment. Improved our ease of delivery for curriculum and student information by building custom learning management software.

VP Product Development & Engineering, Real Digital Media, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2005 - 2015

Managed a team developing Ruby on Rails applications to provide a remote management web application to operate our customer's digital signage networks. Increased application uptime and fault tolerance by building and deploying an AWS infrastructure and software deployment strategy, including multi-zone redundancy. Improved customer support by creating monitoring dashboards and alerts to forecast and resolve issues before customers are impacted. Increased the number of hardware platforms supported by patching Linux hardware drivers for device incompatibilities and missing features. Reduced the complexity of supporting a diverse array of platforms spanning over 30 hardware configurations, from custom system-on-chip to off-the-shelf hardware, including migrations from 32 to 64-bit operating systems and software.

- Ensured continuity of business functions by building disaster recovery policies and code, including
 offsite content and database backups.
- Opened new hardware markets by developing Linux and Android software and custom Linux distributions to run on embedded and PC platforms.
- Increased platform reliability and device uptime of thousands of remote devices by creating a custom Ubuntu-based operating system designed to boot from a single squashfs root filesystem combined with an overlay filesystem allowing for secure and reliable remote upgrades.
- Built online report generator producing CSV, XML, JSON, and PDF reports.
- Expanded markets to new customers by designing and building an interactive editor for creating digital signage presentations containing multi-zone and multi-screen configurations.

Community Leadership

BarCamp Tampa Bay - 2007 to 2017 - Founding member of BarCamp Tampa Bay

Ignite Tampa Bay - 2011 to 2017 - Founding member of Ignite Tampa Bay

Coder Night - 2017 to 2021 - Organized a meetup designed to help developers of all skill levels practice and receive feedback in a supportive and collaborative environment.

Tampa Ruby Brigade - 2006 to Present - Organized the Tampa Ruby Brigade meetup.

Education

University of Arizona

Masters in Management Information Systems

University of Rochester

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science / Applied Mathematics